We're locked in again.
- How do we get out?
- There must be a problem. Relax.
What about Keila?
She was outside. She's not opening up.
That guy must've done something to her.
Keila has a camera.
Damián and Berlin must've seen everything.
Don't jump to conclusions.
Jump to conclusions, Roi?
That guy's the psycho
who locked you in a cage with a dog
and dumped you in the river.
He shot me in the foot.
Keila ran him over,
and now he knows she's a thief.
And what a coincidence,
she was right outside the money cave.
You see?
This is gonna end really fucking badly.
The duke told him we're guests.
He won't touch her.
The light again.
The door opens, the light comes on.
The door closes, the light goes off.
- Roi, look.
- What?
Boys, get to work.
Where's Keila?
With Berlin. Everything's under control.
- Work in here? What if someone comes down?
- Exactly what I said to Berlin.
What if someone comes down?
Risk is part of the beauty of our job,
but we've got an advantage.
Someone's already been down
and left thinking everything's in order.
He's in the kitchen, having coffee.
He doesn't look worried.
I hope no one needs cash
in the next 20 minutes.
So do I,
or you're walking out at gunpoint.
I can't believe it.
Locked in again for the third time.
It's sealed shut.
I hid a camera in the chapel.
They're watching us.
Now we'll see
what's behind this armored door.
- You have the ground-penetrating radar?
- Yep. And echolocation sonar.
We'll build a 3D map
of what's behind the door.
We've got a problem.
The duke's coming!
May I?
I don't mean to interrupt.
I'll just take 30 seconds of your time.
She's so mysterious.
Enigmatic, I'd say.
You're very focused on the task at hand.
Where are the others?
Working for you.
Procuring what we need
through their contacts.
Thermal lances, vehicles, the usual.
Sewage and security systems.
Stuff like that.
"Stuff like that."
Do you have a plan?
We can't wait to share it with you.
Just a few details to finalize.
It's so exciting to be running
the heist of the century.
Even hatching the plan
is a work of art in itself.
I'm dying to hear all the clever details.
We're still chasing
that game-changing spark of genius.
Then I'll leave you to it.
I came to invite you to dinner.
9:30 p.m.
If you need Samuel to take you
to a tailor or a boutique…
Of course not.
I pack for every occasion.
Quite the sense of humor.
I'll see you later.
That nincompoop is a problem.
A problem?
Didn't you see him checking our screens?
How he's marked us and wants to know
our plan down to the last detail?
He seems invested and excited.
A patron's enthusiasm.
No. Make no mistake.
He may play the fool,
dancing on a player piano
like a hallucinating monkey,
but he's got a criminal mind.
He'll force us to rack our brains.
Him snooping around
shows he's neither calm nor confident.
So what do we do?
Design a brilliant plan to steal it
as if we truly meant to.
A real, flawless plan.
I'll handle it myself.
We make a plan and then don't steal it?
Exactly. To blow that idiot away
with a masterpiece of thievery.
Sit down and take notes.
Hack like your life depends on it.
Get me the painting's
departure date from Poland,
its arrival flight in Spain,
and the company transporting it.
What are you doing?
There must be a spring.
Santos opened the door.
A thief enters, and it shuts.
There clearly won't be an obvious button.
The scan's done. Let's go.
How do we get out?
Right on time.
Keila, guide us.
Cooks are on the service stairs.
Come up the east wing.
You packed suits?
Good evening, everyone.
I spent all day thinking how to make this
a soirée to remember.
And bam!
Inspiration struck,
looking at the candelabra
in the mauve room.
So I thought, why not dine
like in the olden days?
As they did in the 18th century
when this palace was finished.
So, bathed in candlelight,
I toast to your success,
which will be mine.
The atmosphere's magical.
Definitely.
- It's the warmth of the candles.
- I love the scent.
Thank you.
Sorry if this isn't the right moment,
but I need to say something important.
These last few days, I've been distant.
I found out Keila had an affair.
What seemed like a casual fling
became something more.
And it's still going on. Romantically.
Bruce, stop. Please.
No, Keila.
Nothing to be ashamed of.
I don't want pity or misunderstandings.
When I found out,
I was obviously devastated.
But she said she loves me.
That I'm wonderful. On another level.
And she doesn't want to leave me.
And I don't want to lose her.
So…
Keila.
Do you want the three of us?
Three of us?
Three people, Roi.
Her,
that guy, and me.
Jesus. Could you be any more of a fool?
You know what, Roi?
I build. I don't destroy.
Something you can't do anymore.
So, Keila?
I'm overwhelmed. I may have tachycardia…
My brain's not working. I don't know.
Maybe we should ask the third party.
We will.
Over coffee or something.
But answer me now.
Well…
Maybe we could explore that.
Yes.
Very well. A toast?
- To the threesome.
- The threesome.
Hell of a way to start dinner.
You have a very modern crew.
Right, darling?
Yes. They really are
a breath of fresh air.
We're more classic, aren't we?
Can you imagine us in a triangle?
- I don't know.
- Come on. Indulge me.
Go with this air of freedom
that's entered our home.
Or imagine, you, me,
and a woman…
from Scandinavia.
- A striking threesome.
- Right.
I pictured two men.
You, my love, of course.
And… I don't know, a man from Brazil?
For instance.
Damián, what do you make of this?
In life, one must choose, duck or a swan.
What does that mean?
The swan is one of the few species
that's monogamous.
And romantic.
And the duck, of course,
is a promiscuous libertine.
The more, the better.
Me? I'm a swan.
A swan?
You're monogamous?
Absolutely.
Though I can imagine
how fun it'd be to be a duck.
No judgment at all.
But for me, love is focusing on someone
and savoring it.
How interesting.
And the leader? What do you think?
If we can enjoy
the love of just one person
who fills us with happiness…
Wine?
…and someone else appears,
and we fall in love with them too,
shouldn't we enjoy double that happiness?
I don't agree.
I believe in communicating glasses.
You can't have two full glasses.
If one is full, it's because another…
was emptied.
Love doesn't need
two or three half glasses.
It needs one.
Full to the brim.
Have you seen the vintage?
"Tomorrow. 8:00 p.m.
Dinner on your boat. For 500,000."
I love your white shirt.
Please. This is unbelievable.
Can someone explain
that dinner in the dark? Good God!
You couldn't tell
the ragout from the truffle!
It's just like something
you'd come up with.
That bubble of decadent beauty,
the candelabra dripping wax,
like some Lord Byron castle.
Right?
One, it wasn't my idea.
Two, I want minimal contact with our mark.
Get to work!
Wait till you hear this.
The duchess is going all out.
While we were making photocopies
like amateurs,
she was redesigning the label
on the wine we drank tonight.
- I don't follow.
- She put the bottle under my nose.
In the fine print,
I saw an invitation for a date.
Faded, like an old label.
Same typography as the '96 Rioja.
How cunning.
And original.
So, she sent you a message
printed on the label.
Bold, isn't she?
Glorious madness, right?
The adrenaline of love and danger.
She asked me to wear a white shirt
if I was interested.
They set the dress code,
so I couldn't go against protocol.
She must've taken it as a yes.
She's coming on strong.
Yes. And you panicked.
It's the responsibility
as a member of the crew and as a man.
For everyone's sake,
I won't meet up with her.
You stubborn swan.
Dear friend, I'm afraid retreat
won't work with the duchess.
Can't you see? She won't give up.
This will blow up in our faces.
So what do you propose?
Go. Make her your best friend.
Buy her ice cream. Talk about your mother.
Nothing kills desire like that.
And remember this.
No kiss…
no crime.
You two analyze the crypt scan data.
I want to know what's behind that door.
May we come in?
What is this adorable thing?
This is Mandarin.
She could be good company for Pomelo.
He's been jealous lately.
Maybe because of me.
This way,
the four of us can go for strolls.
Come in. Close the door.
Let's introduce you,
see how you get along.
Hi, Pomelo.
Here's a friend.
Easy, love.
Look how pretty she is.
Look. Her name's Mandarin.
Sorry if the doorbell
woke you up this late.
No.
You have no idea how happy it makes me
to be woken by the doorbell
in the middle of the night
and see it's you.
Well, you two.
Know why?
Because when you texted me saying
that you were having dinner with the duke,
the truth is,
I wanted to come too.
And I know… it made no sense for me to go.
You're gonna rob him. It's your job, but…
I was still sad.
Silly, right?
And I think it's because…
I'm more in love than I should be.
So I want to ask
what do you feel?
- Sorry.
- Thieves at work. On call 24/7.
Answer.
One second.
Cameron?
- We arrived in Saïdia yesterday.
- Beautiful beach.
I imagine the illustrious passengers
went on a Jeep tour in the desert.
Exactly. They sent the crew ashore too.
They blamed an electrical problem.
They said it'd take six to eight hours.
Only two sailors
and the captain stayed on board.
To avoid suspicion, I said
I wanted to visit Ras Kebdana.
Will I have time?
Why do you want to go there?
My grandfather was from the Chafarinas.
I read you can see the islands
from the cape's lighthouse.
Then today's your lucky day.
I acted excited and hurried off.
But I stayed and watched.
- They didn't see you?
- Not a chance.
I came and went with grocery bags.
Potatoes, bread, fruit…
I'd reach the end of the pier,
dump it, and go back for more.
No one boarded to fix anything.
But something did go aboard,
a pallet of Nigerian rice.
That's the odd part.
I searched the yacht's holds.
There's rice, but it's from Valencia.
So where's the Nigerian rice?
I'll investigate when we weigh anchor.
Keep me informed.
Want to know what I feel?
I feel
what a man feels
who, at dinner with strangers, has been
thinking of you every time love came up
and couldn't get you out of his head
while trying to think
about the security measures of a vault.
And late at night,
he kept thinking of you,
so he thought of making
a midnight trip to La Milagrosa,
a pet shop, to find
the most beautiful rabbit in town.
It wasn't easy.
I had to look up the difference
between a buck and a doe, but I managed.
Then I took a taxi
and arrived at your place at 2:55 a.m.
And from that moment,
I pictured myself climbing the stairs,
heart racing,
ringing your doorbell, and…
losing my mind.
Just to see your face.
So, back to your question,
what would you say a man like that feels?
I think…
he's a little obsessed.
And…
also in love.
Fiery love.
I don't know if this'll work.
She's beat.
Are you tired?
Me? I've never felt less like sleeping.
Great. Because we're going
to make our first plan together.
What are we stealing?
The Lady with an Ermine.
You'll love it.
I know this security system.
The key can be up to 16 characters.
Worst-case scenario,
I crack it in seven minutes.
Strange he'd use something so flimsy,
given that gallery setup.
It makes no sense.
Maybe he values art more than his money.
In there, he's got millions in used bills.
I doubt a mind like his
would settle for this.
Or maybe that door
doesn't need much security.
Keila, the map is rendered.
The data from the GPR
and echolocation sonar are downloaded.
Rhythm, you either got it,
or you don't, baby.
He knows how to move his hips.
- Focus, Keila.
- Sure.
Now we'll see
exactly what's behind that door.
It opens onto a circular hallway.
That's the antechamber
to the secret vault.
Like an igloo.
The GPR indicates
it's made of titanium plates.
Looks impregnable.
- Odd.
- What's odd?
Why not leave it in plain sight?
Why the hallway?
Titanium didn't go with his decor.
The snakeskin carpet is hard to match.
It looks like a bullring, right?
The bull-fighting motif again.
It could be a security ring.
There isn't even a handle
on the inner vault's door.
Or a hydraulic wheel
or anything to open it.
And there's something even stranger.
Look at this.
Double-layer walls.
See?
Why build a cavity between steel walls?
- That weakens the structure.
- Wait.
What did you do?
I used colors to show different densities.
Blue is oxygen.
Red is something with a different density.
Probably gas.
Gas? What for?
Maybe it's a narcotic?
Knowing the duke, it fits, but…
I'd bet it's flammable.
From those six ducts.
Zoom in.
What gas?
Hydrogen, methane, acetylene…
I don't know.
You're saying the duke
built that ring to make a barbecue?
Exactly.
It's an Indiana Jones trap.
He loves those.
Like that angel hand opening the crypt.
So whoever goes in ends up gratinéed?
Like cannelloni?
What kind of madness is that?
Anyone who gets in there, Roi,
has already entered the duke's palace,
gone down into his chapel,
opened his crypt,
walked on his snakeskin carpet,
and cracked his alphanumeric code.
Death would be their just dessert.
That can't be right.
That gas should activate
a hydraulic mechanism or something.
Doors close. Gas floods in.
And you go up in flames.
What is he?
A psychopath? A horror story killer?
We have no proof. I need to analyze it.
I need to think too.
What are you doing here?
I couldn't sleep, so I'm wandering
around your palace, ruminating.
Love?
Heartbreak?
Work?
What keeps you awake?
Mostly work.
It's a great challenge.
My mind's in overdrive.
I know that spiral well.
And I have a remedy that's…
infallible.
Come.
My head's going to explode.
I need to lie down.
I'll take this off and join you.
Where's your dignity?
You're pathetic.
No, you're embarrassing.
It's painful to watch.
You can't grovel harder, dude.
And bringing up a threesome at dinner?
In front of everyone?
So she couldn't say no.
Fucking pathetic.
What's pathetic, Roi?
Saying how you feel,
no matter who's listening?
No, Bruce.
Inviting the girl you love
to fuck another guy in front of you.
It wasn't a ploy.
It's a philosophy.
What philosophy?
Love, Roi. Love.
Normal people are moved
more by love than hate.
That's human nature.
- Yeah.
- And you know what?
I'm sure I'll suffer. Absolutely sure.
But I have to.
Who are you, Gandhi?
A minute ago
you were a clown in an Elvis suit,
goofing off to make her laugh.
It worked, right?
Bad news.
The guy you're up against
is a well-traveled photographer
and graphic designer.
And a fucking paragon of sensitivity.
Bruce.
A clown can't compete.
Listen.
I made Keila fall in love
for the first time at 36.
You know how, Roi?
Talking about her muff.
Whether she waxed. Stupid shit.
Point is, she fell for a clown.
Not some intense, deep guy.
So maybe, Roi,
art is overrated.
Here it is.
My secret to stop the mental turbine…
and anxiety.
Come, my love.
Come.
This is Prince.
See? They talk.
Touch him.
That's it.
Touch his mane.
Talk to him. Let him know your voice.
- How are you, Prince?
- Easy.
- What is it?
- Hug him.
Hug him.
But…
Go on. He won't do a thing.
Like this?
Not like that. Watch.
Harder. Watch me.
He has to feel your heat.
When you hear his heartbeat,
feel your own.
You'll see. They fall into step.
Now you. Do it.
Focus on breathing.
Sync yours with his.
You'll see. Soon you'll both breathe
13 times a minute.
Let him guide you. The tempo, the pauses…
The depth of it.
Your body will start releasing oxytocin.
And you'll feel
extraordinary peace.
I already feel it.
Enjoy it, then.
Because peace is going extinct,
like all good things.
Isn't that right, Prince?
And so am I.
Pardon?
Well, the haste,
the phones,
the ménages à trois…
All of it will end the world
you and I belong to.
I'm a swan too, you know?
We are…
the monogamous horse whisperers.
I don't know what to think.
Neither do I.
This conversation deserves a pairing.
What are you saying?
Nothing. I just want
to set a few ground rules.
About this guy, Claudio.
Here, Claudio is…
the guest artist.
You follow?
I know we're all learning, but
I can't give you an inch
and have you take a mile.
I don't want to take a mile.
You're generous,
but I don't know how to handle this.
I feel more maladjusted than usual.
What if it's a bad idea?
People are supposed to choose.
This feels selfish.
Keila, relax.
I only want to set a few boundaries.
What boundaries?
Well…
Don't share an umbrella if it rains.
No sharing ice cream.
Or popcorn at the movies.
One bucket each.
No karaoke duets.
I don't know, Keila…
I'd rather you didn't…
show him your virtual reality world.
You said I was the only one
who'd seen it, Keila.
Right?
Or did you show him already?
Three Mauser shots
You ran, jet black, saving my life
What you did for me
Horse friend, I won't forget
I couldn't save you
That bitter knowledge makes me cry
That's why, you jet black horse
I will never forget you
I'll tell you something
I think you'll like,
although it may bother you.
Go ahead.
Unfortunately,
you are not becoming extinct.
- You don't say.
- You're not.
There are more specimens like you.
- You saw them?
- Yes.
- One moment.
This conversation deserves a new wine.
A friend of mine is just like you.
He's a sybarite,
wine enthusiast, lover of beauty,
paintings, art…
A Tuscan Chianti would be perfect,
but in clean glasses.
Your glass, sir.
- Thank you.
So tell me.
What else in your friend resembles me?
He shares with you
having a unique, personal
and immovable way of seeing the world,
a universe of your own
where you arrange all other mortals.
- Are you calling me egocentric?
- Yes.
Of course. Narcissistic, egocentric.
But fascinating.
A person who fills everything
with their presence,
with a catalyst energy
that teaches you to enjoy life.
And when you exit a room or a stable,
the world seems empty,
absent.
And who is that friend of yours?
One who's awake right now,
looking for the spark of genius
for your robbery.
Will he find it?
He always does.
Always?
He's infallible.
I want to show you something. Come.
Wait.
Where are we going?
To the chapel.
All my forebears are buried here.
Five generations of Hermosos de Medina.
The twins are also here,
Leopoldo and Armando.
Four years old.
A tragedy.
Grab that little angel's hand.
What?
Grab the arm on that statue and pull down.
You first.
What?
What do you think?
Surprising decorations for a crypt.
It's a crypt under another crypt.
Another one of my secrets.
Here I keep my third treasure.
Would you be able to take it from me?
The third?
The first was the art collection
and you already trespassed it.
Well.
The second is my wife.
And here…
Here
is my vault.
Tell me, could you leave me with nothing?
Well,
everything's possible
in the art of thieving.
The art?
Turn around.
You can turn around now.
Ta-da!
Go in.
Don't you trust me?
I don't know if this is appropriate.
I'm telling you my deepest secrets.
And now you won't trust me?
Cross that line.
Go ahead.
Do it.
Boo.
Look at me.
Do you really think
you could get this far by yourself?
Subtitle translation by:
Soledad Etchemendy